<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business Process Engineering for Machine Learning Projects on Machine Learning Business Processes</title>
    <link>./</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business Process Engineering for Machine Learning Projects on Machine Learning Business Processes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:51:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>./about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./about/</guid>
      <description>We are a collective that has decades of experience in delivering working software projects.
Phillip Henry Phillip received his BSc in physics from Imperial College and then spent the next 30 years consulting for the likes of Goldman Sachs and Vodafone. He spent a year as a Senior Data Scientist at Erste Bank in Vienna where he focussed on delivery. He specialises in Big Data technologies.
Mauro Talevi Mauro&amp;rsquo;s PhD was in Monte Carlo simulations in Theoretical High Energy Physics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London MLOps hosts our presentation</title>
      <link>./news/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./news/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Dr Chris Monit and Phillip Henry discuss their experience bringing an ML model to production at the London MLOps meetup.
Chris and Phill show how taking software engineering best practices and applying them to a machine learning project, they successfully delivered on time and on budget.
They detail the problems they had and how they overcame them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pysynic</title>
      <link>./news/pysynic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./news/pysynic/</guid>
      <description>We release PySynic to PyPI to facilitate the use of synthetic data that can be used to test ML pipelines.
Testing ML pipelines is still an immature discipline. We&amp;rsquo;re bring testing best practices to ML with a lightweight framework that helps generated synthetic data. Synthetic data is GDPR friendly and can be run in any environment. With this data, ML practitioners can write robust tests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HSJ Awards</title>
      <link>./news/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./news/awards/</guid>
      <description>Our work was a finalist for the Best Healthcare Analytics Project for the NHS as nominated by the Health Service Journal.
The HSJ nominated Actionable Insights, a machine learning pipeline, recoginising the work on identifying ethnic and socioeconomic groups who had clinical outcomes worse than the majority.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLOps: debugging a pipeline</title>
      <link>./blog/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 11:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./blog/debugging/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare in England is broken down into about 40 regions. For each region, we want to measure the differences in clinical outcomes conditioned on the ethnic and socioeconomic categories of the patients. To do this, we feed the data for each health region into a Spark GLM (Generalized Linear Models).
The problem Everything was fine with our pipeline for six months before it started to blow up with:
Caused by: org.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for effective MLOps</title>
      <link>./blog/mlops_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 11:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./blog/mlops_tips/</guid>
      <description>Some miscellaneous tips I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered after over a year of being hands-on with a clinical ETL pipeline.
Technology Set up a local dev environment (Git, Pip, IDE of choice, Python environment etc). Being able to test locally cannot be more important. For instance, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Palantir&amp;rsquo;s Foundry but since it&amp;rsquo;s just a wrapper around Spark, you can have a full, locally run, test suite using PySpark.
If you can&amp;rsquo;t get the data on your laptop (GDPR etc), use simulated data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLOps debugging: an example</title>
      <link>./blog/debugging2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 11:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./blog/debugging2/</guid>
      <description>In our ML pipeline, we use generalized linear models to calculate the odds of certain clinical outcomes. We showed this to the client but odds were hard for them to understand. &amp;ldquo;Can we have probabilities instead?&amp;rdquo; they asked.
So, having trained the GLMs, we fit the same data and calculate the average probabilities for each cohort. We then bastardise the data to create the counterfactuals For example, socioeconomic status is of interest so let&amp;rsquo;s make everybody the same level (counterfactual) then make our predictions again and compare with the factual results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Studies</title>
      <link>./cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./cases/</guid>
      <description>NHS/CF We reduced time to market, increased model reliability and built a process that easily managed changing requirements mid project.
We did this by teaching best practices to two data scientists with PhDs in STEM subjects.
The model was delivered on time and on budget.
Since it came with a robust suite of automated tests, production issues were easily dealt with after sign-off.
The project was so successful, it was a finalist in the Best Healthcare Analytics Project for the NHS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>./contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>./contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: ph@odinconsultants.co.uk
Phone: +44 (0)7958 679 063</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
